<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Generated Blog by Dathan capturing his random thoughts</title><link>https://dathan.github.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content on Generated Blog by Dathan capturing his random thoughts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 11:38:59 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dathan.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Rituals in DevOps for T eams</title><link>https://dathan.github.io/blog/posts/rituals_in_dev_ops/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 11:38:59 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://dathan.github.io/blog/posts/rituals_in_dev_ops/</guid><description>Every Monday, leadership pass downs happen, then we have a standup, then we talk about the pages of the past week. To aid in this ritual, we have an automated Confluent Page, generated from a cronjob that documents all the PagerDuty&amp;rsquo;s pages. The program reads data over PagerDuty&amp;rsquo;s API and writes to Confluence API running as a cronjob in Kubernetes.
These actions described since performed at a regular cadence is a ritual.</description></item><item><title>Tailscale Kubernetes</title><link>https://dathan.github.io/blog/posts/tailscale-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 17:33:37 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://dathan.github.io/blog/posts/tailscale-kubernetes/</guid><description>Last year I wrote a quick docker image and helm chart to install tailscale into your Kubernetes cluster. My particular use case was reaching devices between multiple colliding networks from the cloud to a physical location someplace around the world. Tailscale is perfect for this use-case, and putting together that project was fun and informative.
Today I read this post by Maisem Ali and Maya Kaczorowski. A fantastic combination of features and abilities that make reaching services in a Kubernetes cluster easy.</description></item><item><title>Some Thoughts on Github Hugo</title><link>https://dathan.github.io/blog/posts/some-thoughts-on-github-hugo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 18:11:46 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://dathan.github.io/blog/posts/some-thoughts-on-github-hugo/</guid><description>GitHub pages is new for me and I was not aware that the contents of GitHub pages site can be based on branches and path combos. Using the GitHub action and reading the documentation, the action to build is on main. Main is the default branch. The action also executes hugo and publishes the hugo generated site to the root of the gh-pages branch. As a result, a silent step that was needed to automated this blog post.</description></item><item><title>I want to write an informative log ...</title><link>https://dathan.github.io/blog/posts/my-first-post/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 16:48:51 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://dathan.github.io/blog/posts/my-first-post/</guid><description>In the past, I ran a blog at mysqldba.blogspot.com, but I started to move in different directions away from just the database layer but focused on truely the entire stack. I am doing much more than MySQL, but I still keep up to date and use it in my personal projects. Since I moved into the entire stack, I basically gave up my focus and to an extent my expertise in mySQL.</description></item></channel></rss>